William Safire Papers
William Safire Papers
- Subject files
  - Privacy
    - Contact phone number (Box 294)
    - Cookies (Box 294)
      See also Subject file Computers: Cookies.
    - Customer surveillance (Box 294)
    - Data sharing, 2 folders (Box 294)
    - Essays by Safire (Box 294)
    - Financial, 3 folders (Box 294)
    - Global Privacy Symposium, 2 folders (Box 294)
    - Government intrusion (Box 295)
    - H.R. 4049 (Box 295)
    - Homeland security (Box 295)
    - Identity theft (Box 295)
    - Implants (Box 295)
    - Information brokers (Box 295)
    - Internet, 4 folders (Box 295)
    - Intrusion explosion (Box 295)
    - Language of (Box 295)
    - Lingo (Box 295)
    - Medical, 6 folders (Box 296)
    - National identification card (Box 296)
    - Notices (Box 296)
    - Online profiling (Box 296)
    - Opt in/opt out (Box 296)
    - Personal (Box 296)
    - Personal, 3 folders (Box 297)
    - Phones (Box 297)
    - Privacy journal (Box 297)
    - Rotenberg, Marc (Box 297)
    - Secrecy (Box 297)
    - Security technologies (Box 297)
    - Social security numbers, 3 folders (Box 297)
    - Software (Box 297)
    - Strategic Medical Intelligence (SMI) (Box 297)
    - Students, 2 folders (Box 297)
    - Students (Box 298)
    - Surveillance cameras (Box 298)
    - Thermal imaging (Box 298)
    - Traffic cameras (Box 298)
    - Wiretaps (Box 298)
    - Workplace (Box 298)
  - Privilege (Box 298)
  - Program trading (Box 298)
  - Project Sapphire (Box 298)
  - Prostate (Box 298)
  - Protecting America's Freedom in the Information Age (Box 298)
  - Prozac (Box 298)
  - Public radio (Box 298)
  - Publications (Box 298)
  - Publicity, 3 folders (Box 298)
  - Publicity (Box 299)
  - Publicity (Box 491)
  - Pulitzer Prize
    - [General], 7 folders (Box 299)
    - [General], 7 folders (Box 300)
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 301)
    - Administrator's reports, 3 folders (Box 301)
    - Board, 4 folders (Box 301)
    - Board, 3 folders (Box 302)
    - Board co-chair (Box 302)
    - Drama (Box 302)
    - Durant, Walter (Box 302)
    - Entries (Box 302)
    - Fiction (Box 302)
    - Goodwin, Doris Kearns (Box 302)
    - Jurors (Box 302)
    - Jury reports
      - Journalism, 3 folders (Box 302)
      - Journalism, 5 folders (Box 303)
      - Letters, drama, and music, 3 folders (Box 303)
      - Letters, drama, and music, 2 folders (Box 304)
    - Lewis, Anthony (Box 304)
    - Luncheon (Box 304)
    - Music (Box 304)
    - Non fiction (Box 304)
    - On-line, 2 folders (Box 304)
    - Poetry (Box 304)
    - Spot news (Box 304)
    - Vacancies (Box 304)
  - Pulitzer Prizes 1996
    - Administrator's reports (Oversize 7)
    - Jury reports
      - Journalism (Oversize 7)
      - Journalism Entries Index (Oversize 7)
      - Letters, Drama, and Music (Oversize 7)
      - Letters Entries Index (Oversize 7)
    - Nominations
      - Commentary (Oversize 7)
      - Criticism (Oversize 7)
      - Editorial cartooning, 2 volumes (Oversize 7)
      - Journalism, 2 volumes (Oversize 7)
  - Pulitzer Prizes 1997
    - Administrator's reports (Oversize 8)
    - Jury reports
      - Journalism (Oversize 8)
      - Journalism Entries Index (Oversize 8)
      - Letters, Drama, and Music (Oversize 8)
      - Letters Entries Index (Oversize 8)
    - Nominations
      - Commentary (Oversize 8)
      - Criticism (Oversize 8)
      - Drama
        - How, Tina. "Pride's Crossing" (Oversize 8)
        - Margulies, Donald. "Collected Stories" (Oversize 8)
        - Reynolds, Jonathan. "Stonewall Jackson's House" (Oversize 8)
        - Uhry, Alfred. "The Last Night of Ballyhoo" (Oversize 8)
      - Editorial writing (Oversize 8)
      - Feature writing (Oversize 8)
      - International reporting (bound with an Editorial writing entry) (Oversize 8)
      - Journalism, 2 volumes (Oversize 8)
  - Pulitzer Prizes 1998
    - Administrator's reports (Oversize 9)
    - Jury reports
      - Journalism (Oversize 9)
      - Journalism Entries Index (Oversize 9)
      - Letters, Drama, and Music (Oversize 9)
      - Letters Entries Index (Oversize 9)
    - Nominations
      - Commentary (Oversize 9)
      - Criticism (Oversize 9)
      - Drama
        - Freed, Amy. "Freedomland" (Oversize 9)
        - Greenberg, Richard. "Three Days of Rain" (Oversize 9)
        - Vogel, Paula. "How I Learned to Drive" (Oversize 9)
      - Editorial cartooning (Oversize 9)
      - Editorial writing (Oversize 9)
      - Feature writing (Oversize 9)
      - Journalism, 2 volumes (Oversize 9)
  - Punctuator's World (Box 304)
  - Putin, Vladimir (Box 305)
  - Quebec (Box 305)
  - Rabin, [Yitzhak] - notes (Box 305)
  - Racketeering, See RICO.
  - Radek, Lee (Box 305)
  - Radio Free Asia, 2 folders (Box 305)
  - Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty, 3 folders (Box 305)
  - Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty, 7 folders (Box 306)
  - Radio Shack portable computer (Box 306)
  - Rapoport, Bernard (Box 306)
  - Rappaport, Bruce
    - [General] (Box 306)
    - Iran/contra reactions (Box 306)
  - Rare books (Box 491)
  - Read, Allen Walker (Box 306)
  - Reagan, Nancy (Box 306)
  - Reagan, Ronald, book (Box 306)
    See also Subject files Deaver, Michael: Reagan, Ronald; McCrary, Tex: Eisenhower, Dwight D. and Ronald Reagan.
  - Reed, Joseph V. (Box 307)
  - Reeves, Samuel T. (Box 307)
  - Refugees (Box 307)
  - Refusals (Box 307)
  - Regrets, 3 folders (Box 307)
  - Reich, Otto (Box 307)
  - Reno, Janet
    - [General] (Box 307)
    - Dellinger, Walter (Box 307)
    - Gore, Al (Box 307)
    - Waco, TX (Box 307)
  - Republican National Convention (Box 307)
  - Republican party (Box 307)
  - Republican primaries (Box 307)
  - Reston, Scotty (Box 307)
  - Resumés
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 308)
    - Dodd, Delores (Box 308)
    - Farrish, Diane (Box 308)
    - Gibbens, Elizabeth (Box 308)
    - Laudon, Isabelle (Box 308)
    - Lawrence, Rebecca (Box 308)
    - Lubell, Karen (Box 308)
    - Phillips, Elizabeth B. (Box 308)
    - Reynolds, Andrea (Box 308)
    - Robinson, Angela (Box 308)
    - Rumford, E. Marie (Box 308)
  - Riady, James and Mochtar Riady, 3 folders (Box 308)
    See also Subject file Lippo: Riady, Mochtar.
  - Riady, James and Mochtar Riady (Box 309)
  - Rich, Marc (Box 309)
  - RICO, 3 folders (Box 309)
  - Rinfret Futures (Box 309)
  - Ritter, Scott (Box 309)
  - Robb, Charles (Box 309)
  - Robertson, Pat (Box 309)
  - Robertson / North (Box 309)
  - Robinson, Gil, 2 folders (Box 309)
  - Rockefeller, Jay (Box 310)
  - Room 16 (Box 310)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Man in the Arena (Box 491)
  - Rose, Charlie (Box 310)
  - Rosenthal, A. M. (Box 310)
  - Rosenthal, Eelo Bosch van (Box 310)
  - Rosenthal, Jack (Box 310)
  - Rostenkowski, Dan, Russia (Box 310)
  - Rover, Edward (Box 310)
  - Rowen-Wolf (Box 310)
  - Rowny, Edward, 2 folders (Box 310)
  - Royalty statements (Box 310)
  - Rubin, Anne (Box 310)
  - Rubin, Nancy and Miles (Box 310)
  - Ruff, Charles (Box 310)
  - Rulon-Miller Books (Box 310)
  - Rumsfeld, Donald (Box 310)
  - Russia
    See also Subject files American Committee on U.S.-Soviet Relations; Disunion, USSR; KGB; Soviet Union.
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 311)
    - Latvia (Box 311)
    - Lukin, Vladimir (Box 311)
    - Mafia, See Subject file Mafia, Russia.
    - NATO (Box 311)
    - Policy (Box 311)
  - Sacks, Oliver (Box 311)
  - Safir, Andrew (Box 311)
  - Safire, name derivation (Box 311)
  - Safire family relatives (Box 311)
  - Safire Public Relations (Box 491)
  - Safire Public Relations, clipping about (Box 520)
  - Safire, Leonard, fan mail (Box 491)
  - Safire, Lily (Box 311)
  - Safire, Mark (Box 311)
    See also Wedding, Mark Safire and Karen Hirschfield.
  - Safire, Peter (Box 311)
  - Safire, William
    - Cartoons (Box 311)
    - German analysis (Box 311)
    - Lexis-Nexis (Oversize 10)
    - Name derivation (Box 311)
    - Satire (Box 312)
  - Saint Petersburg (Box 312)
  - Sallygate (Box 312)
  - Same-sex marriage (Box 312)
  - Samuel Shapiro and Company Korean Furniture (Box 312)
  - Saudi Arabia
    See also Subject file Bandar bin Sultan, Prince.
    - [General] (Box 312)
    - Succession (Box 312)
  - Scalia, Antonin (Box 312)
  - Scharping, Rudolf (Box 312)
  - Schemann, Serge (Box 312)
  - School prayer (Box 312)
  - Schorr, Daniel
    - [General] (Box 312)
    - Book introduction (Box 312)
  - Schultz, George (Box 312)
  - Schwarzkopf, Norman (Box 312)
  - Scott, Marsha (Box 312)
  - Scowcroft, Brent (Box 312)
  - Screenplay (Box 312)
  - Secession (Box 313)
  - Secrecy (Box 313)
    See also Subject file Privacy: Secrecy.
  - Secret tapings, JFK (Box 313)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) (Box 313)
  - Sedition (Box 313)
  - Senate Governmental Affairs Committee (SGAC) (Box 313)
  - Senate intelligence (Box 313)
  - Senate races (Box 313)
  - Seven days (Box 313)
  - Sexual harassment (Box 313)
  - Seymour Jr., William North (Box 313)
  - Shalikashvili, John (Box 313)
  - Shamir, Yitzhak (Box 313)
  - Sharon, Ariel
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 314)
    - Belgium (Box 313)
  - Shelby, [Richard], leaks (Box 314)
  - Shelby, Richard (Box 314)
  - Shen, Jueren (Box 314)
  - Sherburne, Jane, task list (Box 314)
  - Shield of Achilles (Box 314)
  - Shields, Rosemary, administrative, 2 folders (Box 314)
  - Shultz, George (Box 314)
  - Siegal, Al (Box 314)
  - Simon, Paul (Box 314)
  - Simpson, O.J. (Box 314)
  - Sinatra, Frank (Box 314)
  - Singapore
    See also Subejct files Deaver, Michael: Singapore; Travel: Singapore.
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 314)
    - [General], 7 folders (Box 315)
    - [General], 4 folders (Box 316)
    - [General], 13 folders (Box 316)
    - Caning, 2 folders (Box 316)
    - Chang Heng Chee (Box 316)
    - Contemplacion, Flor (Box 316)
    - Darrow, Katherine (Box 316)
    - Debate (Box 316)
    - Essays by Safire, William (Box 316)
    - Goh Chok Tong (Box 316)
    - House, Karen (Box 316)
    - International Herald Tribune (Box 317)
    - Internet (Box 317)
    - Lee Kuan Yew, 6 folders (Box 317)
    - Letters from (Box 317)
    - Mail (Box 317)
    - Nixon, Richard (Box 317)
    - Seow, Francis T. (Box 317)
    - Williams College (Box 317)
    - Wrage, Stephen D. (Box 317)
  - Skoda Plzen (Box 318)
  - Slovakia (Box 318)
  - Smallpox (Box 318)
  - Smoot-Hawley Tariff (Box 318)
  - Snooping (Box 318)
  - Snoring (Box 318)
  - Snow, John (Box 318)
  - Social security, 3 folders (Box 318)
  - Software (Box 318)
    See also Subject file Privacy: Software.
  - Solomon, Gerald B. H. (Box 318)
  - South Africa (Box 318)
  - South Carolina (Box 318)
  - South Paws Veterinary Hospital (Box 318)
  - Sovereignty (Box 318)
  - Soviet Union
    See also Subject files American Committee on U.S.-Soviet Relations; Disunion, USSR; KGB; Russia.
    - Arbatov, Georgi (Box 318)
    - Baltics (Box 318)
      See also Subject file Baltic states.
    - Baltics, 3 folders (Box 319)
    - Bank of Credit and Commerce International (BCCI)
      - [General], 2 folders (Box 319)
      - Media (Box 319)
      - Rogers, Edward (Box 319)
    - Soviet Union / Christianity (Box 319)
    - Communist Party Congress (Box 319)
    - Defense spending (Box 319)
    - Jewry (Box 319)
    - Latvia (Box 319)
    - Legvold, Robert (Box 319)
    - Lithuania (Box 319)
    - Miners, 2 folders (Box 320)
    - Moscow (Box 320)
    - Moscow summit (Box 320)
      See also Subject file Summits: Moscow.
    - Percentage
      - [General], 2 folders (Box 320)
      - Birman, Igor, 2 folders (Box 320)
      - Military, 2 folders (Box 320)
      - Rowen, Henry S. (Box 320)
    - Red Army (Box 321)
    - U.S. relations (Box 321)
    - Vilnius (Box 321)
  - Speakers Worldwide, Inc. (Box 321)
  - Speaking engagements
    - [General] (Box 321)
    - Thank-you's (Box 321)
  - Speaking fees (Box 321)
  - Special counsel (Box 321)
  - Special prosecutor, 2 folders (Box 321)
  - Spector, Ron (Box 321)
  - Spectrum (Box 321)
  - Speechwriters (Box 321)
    See also Subject file Bush, George W.: Speechwriters.
  - Speed limit (Box 321)
  - Spookery (Box 321)
  - Sporkin, Stanley (Box 321)
  - Spring revival (Box 321)
  - Star wars (Box 321)
  - Star wars, 3 folders (Box 322)
    See also Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI).
  - Starr, Kenneth (Box 322)
  - State Department, See Subject files Eavesdrop, State Department; Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): State Department; Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): State Department, John Kelly; Israel: State Department.
  - Steadman, Marty (Box 322)
  - Stealth program (Box 322)
  - Stepashin, Sergei (Box 322)
  - Stephanopoulos, George (Box 322)
  - Stephens, [?] (Box 322)
  - Stevens, Art (Box 322)
  - Stewart, Jon (Box 322)
  - Stewart, Martha, 2 folders (Box 322)
  - Stone, Oliver (Box 322)
  - Strait of Hormuz (Box 322)
  - Strategic Defense Initiative [SDI] (Box 322)
    See also Star wars.
  - Strategic Influence, Department of Defense (Box 322)
  - Student testing (Box 322)
  - Sturua, Melor (Box 323)
  - Succession (Box 323)
    See also Subject file Saudi Arabia: Succession.
  - Sudoplatov, Pavel (Box 323)
  - Suerth, Philip (Box 323)
  - Sullivan, Andrew (Box 323)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur O. (Box 323)
  - Summer holiday (Box 323)
  - Summits
    - Moscow, 2 folders (Box 323)
      See also Subejct file Soviet Union: Moscow summit.
    - Washington, D.C., 2 folders (Box 323)
  - Sununu, John
    - [General] (Box 323)
    - Arabs (Box 323)
  - Sweeney, John J., 2 folders (Box 323)
  - Switzerland (Box 323)
  - Syracuse University
    - [General], 7 folders (Box 324)
    - [General], 7 folders (Box 325)
    - [General], 6 folders (Box 326)
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 327)
    - Academic affairs (Box 327)
    - Academic plan (Box 327)
    - Acquisitions/appraisals/donations (Box 327)
    - Advisory board - Washington, DC (Box 327)
    - Arents Award, See Wohl, Bernard J..
    - Board of trustees, 2 folders (Box 327)
    - Board of trustees, 7 folders (Box 328)
    - Board of trustees handbook (Box 328)
    - Board of visitors (Box 328)
    - Calendar, 3 folders (Box 329)
      It is unclear why this is material was referred to as "Syracuse University calendar." The calendars appear to be Safire's schedule in general, not specific to SU.
    - Campus plan (Oversize 10)
    - Cantor, Nancy (Box 329)
    - Cobbett, William (Box 329)
    - College of Arts and Sciences (Box 329)
    - Commencement address (Box 329)
    - Conflict of interest (Box 329)
    - Conservation (Box 329)
    - Correspondence (Box 329)
    - Daily Orange (Box 329)
    - Dana Foundation (Box 329)
      See also Subject file Dana Foundation.
    - Development (Box 329)
    - Endowed chair (Box 329)
    - English department (Box 329)
    - Experts list (Box 330)
    - Financial reports (Box 330)
    - Information studies (Box 330)
    - Institutional advancement (Box 330)
    - Intellectual property (Box 330)
    - Karr, Mary (Box 330)
    - Lectures (Box 330)
    - Library, 4 folders (Box 330)
    - Library associates (Box 330)
    - Library Connection (Box 330)
    - Menschel, Robert B. (Box 330)
    - Miami University (Box 330)
    - Miller, David (Box 330)
    - Morgan Stanley (Box 330)
    - National Association of Real Estate Investment Trusts (Box 330)
    - National rankings (Box 330)
    - New York Mercantile Exchange (Box 330)
    - Office of Development (Box 330)
    - Personal (Box 330)
    - Press (Box 330)
    - Prospectus (Box 331)
    - Pulitzer (Box 331)
    - Rock, Arthur (Box 331)
    - Rubin, Dean David M. (Box 331)
    - Safire Celebration (Oversize 10)
    - Safire Chair (Box 331)
    - Safire Reading Room (Box 331)
    - School of Information Studies (Box 331)
    - Shaw, Kenneth A. (Box 331)
    - Society of Fellows membership (Box 331)
    - Speakers (Box 331)
    - Special Collections (Box 331)
    - Student Affairs Committee (Box 331)
    - Syracuse Record (Box 331)
    - Syria, 2 folders (Box 331)
    - Theater and arts (Box 331)
    - Tolley Society (Box 331)
    - Treasurer (Box 331)
    - Trustee leaflet (Oversize 10)
    - Western Kentucky University (Box 331)
    - Wisconsin Manufacturing and Commerce (Box 331)
    - Wohl, Bernard J., Arents Award (Box 331)
    - Wrestling and gymnastics (Box 331)
    - Writing program (Box 331)
  - Syria, See Subject files China: Syria; Syracuse University: Syria.
  - Taipei (Box 331)
  - Taiwan (Box 331)
  - Talking points (Box 331)
  - Tamraz, Roger (Box 331)
  - Tamraz, Roger (Box 332)
  - Tapes (Box 332)
  - Tax cuts (Box 332)
  - Taxes (Box 332)
    See also Subject file Flat tax.
  - Teachout, Terry (Box 332)
  - Telephone logs (Oversize 11)
  - Telephone logs (Box 480)
  - Telephone logs (Box 481)
  - Telephone logs, 4 folders (Box 491)
  - Telephone logs, 12 folders (Box 492)
  - Terrorism Information Awareness (TIA) (Box 332)
  - Thank You, Anna (Box 332)
  - Thank you's (Box 332)
  - Theory (Box 332)
  - Think tanks (Box 332)
  - Thomas, Clarence (Box 332)
  - Thompson, Fred, 2 folders (Box 332)
  - Thornburgh, Richard, 2 folders (Box 332)
  - Threats (Box 332)
  - Thurmond, Strom
    See Deaver, Michael: Thurmond, Strom.
  - Tibet (Box 332)
  - Tierney, John (Box 332)
  - Time-Warner merger (Box 333)
  - Times books (Box 333)
  - Times fax (Box 333)
  - Tipping Point (Box 333)
  - Titles (Box 333)
  - Tolchin, Charles P., 2 folders (Box 333)
  - Total Information Awareness [TIA], 2 folders (Box 333)
  - Total Information Awareness [TIA], 2 folders (Box 333)
  - Toys - antiques (Box 333)
  - Travel
    - Africa - aborted, 1978-1981 (Box 333)
    - Asia, November, 1987 (Box 333)
    - Asia, November, 1987; 4 folders (Box 334)
    - Asia, September 1990; 4 folders (Box 334)
    - Budapest, Prague, Paris, London, March, 1993 (Box 334)
    - China, November 1987 (Box 334)
      See also China trip.
    - Europe, 1982 (Box 334)
    - Europe, 1985 (Box 334)
    - Europe, February 1982 (Box 334)
    - Europe, July 1974; 2 folders (Box 334)
    - Europe, June 1982 (Box 334)
    - Hungary (Box 334)
    - Israel, 4 folders (Box 334)
    - Israel (Box 335)
    - Lech, Austria, February 1993 (Box 335)
    - London (Box 335)
    - London, April 1988 (Box 335)
    - London, April 1991 (Box 335)
    - London, April-May 1989 (Box 335)
    - London, August 1993 (Box 335)
    - London, December 1985 (Box 335)
    - London, December 1986 (Box 335)
    - London, December 1990 (Box 335)
    - London, January 1993 (Box 335)
    - London, June 1986 (Box 335)
    - London, June 1987 (Box 335)
    - London, June 1990 (Box 335)
    - London, June 1997 (Box 335)
    - London, March 1991 (Box 335)
    - London, March 1994 (Box 335)
    - London, May 1992 (Box 335)
    - London, September 1989 (Box 335)
    - London, September 1992 (Box 335)
    - Monaco, October 1997 (Box 335)
    - Moscow, December 1993; 2 folders (Box 336)
    - Moscow, June 1996; 2 folders (Box 336)
    - Paris, Warsaw, Riga, June 1993 (Box 336)
    - Poland (Box 336)
    - Russia, 1998 (Box 336)
    - Russia, May 1995 (Box 336)
    - Singapore, November 1987 (Box 336)
    - South Korea, November 1987 (Box 336)
    - Soviet Union, November 1991 (Box 337)
  - Travelgate (Box 337)
  - Trial lawyers (Box 337)
  - Tribunals, 3 folders (Box 337)
  - Triplett, Bill (Box 337)
  - Trulock, Notra (Box 337)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Box 337)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Box 338)
  - Tulane (Box 338)
  - Turkey
    - [General], 6 folders (Box 338)
    - Azerbaijan (Box 339)
    - Israel (Box 339)
    - Politics (Box 339)
  - Twenty-fifth amendment (Box 339)
  - Ukraine (Box 339)
  - Ulbrich, Jeffrey (Box 339)
  - Unidentified (Box 339)
  - United Nations
    - [General] (Box 339)
    - Oil for Food
      See also Subject file Oil for Food.
      - [General], 4 folders (Box 339)
      - [General], 6 folders (Box 340)
      - Annan, Kofi, 2 folders (Box 340)
      - Blas, Jimmy D. (Box 340)
      - Coleman, Norm (Box 340)
      - Criticism (Box 340)
      - Hyde, [Henry] (Box 340)
      - Independent Inquiry Committee report
        - Vol I (Box 341)
        - Vol II, 2 folders (Box 341)
        - Vol III, 2 folders (Box 341)
        - Vol IV (Box 341)
        - Vol IV, 2 folders (Box 341)
        - Third interim report (Box 341)
      - Mortimer, Edward (Box 342)
      - Murphy, Richard (Box 342)
      - Sevan, Benon V. (Box 342)
      - U.S. attorney (Box 342)
      - Volcher, [Paul A.] (Box 342)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA) (Box 342)
    See also Subject file Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): USIA.
  - Unpublished collections (Box 342)
  - Urdang, Laurence (Box 342)
    See also Verbatim.
  - USS Cole, 2 folders (Box 342)
  - USSR, See Russia; Soviet Union.
  - Verbatim, Laurence Urdang (Box 342)
  - Veterans, 2 folders (Box 342)
  - Vice President Ideas (Box 342)
  - Vidal, Gore (Box 342)
  - Voice of America (VOA), 3 folders (Box 343)
  - Volcker, Paul (Box 343)
  - Vouchers, 2 folders (Box 343)
  - Waldheim, Kurt, 2 folders (Box 343)
  - Waldheim, Kurt, "Wartime Years: A Documentation", 2 folders (Oversize 14)
  - Wall Street (Box 343)
  - Wallach, E. Robert, 2 folders (Box 344)
  - Wang Jun (Box 344)
  - War Powers, 3 folders (Box 344)
  - War Powers Act, 2 folders (Box 344)
  - Warner, John (Box 344)
  - Warranties (Box 344)
  - Washington, George (Box 344)
  - Watergate (Box 345)
  - Weapons of mass destruction (Box 345)
  - Website, See Williamsafire.com.
  - Wedding, Mark Safire and Karen Hirschfield, 2 folders (Box 345)
  - Wednesday Ten
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 345)
    - Goldman, Mort (Box 345)
    - Obituaries (Box 345)
  - WEF, See World Economic Forum.
  - Wei Jingsheng (Box 345)
    See also Subject file China: Wei Jingsheng.
  - Weinberg, Steven (Box 345)
  - Weld, William (Box 345)
  - Welliver, Judson (Box 345)
  - Wen Ho Lee (Box 345)
  - Wen Ho Lee (Box 346)
  - Western Governors Association (Box 346)
  - White House policy planning (Box 346)
  - White House royalism (Box 346)
  - Whitewater, 5 folders (Box 346)
  - Whitewater, 2 folders (Box 347)
  - Whitman, Christine Todd (Box 347)
  - Who's Who in America (Box 347)
  - Wick, Charles Z. (Box 347)
  - Wilder, Douglas (Box 347)
  - Williamsafire.com (Box 347)
  - Wilson, Pete, 2 folders (Box 347)
  - The Wind Done Gone (Box 347)
  - Wire taps (Box 347)
  - Wirt, Wilma (Box 347)
  - Wolf Jr., Charles (Box 347)
  - Wolfowitz, Paul (Box 347)
  - Wollenstonecraft, Mary (Box 347)
  - Woolsey, James (Box 347)
  - Workstations (Box 347)
  - World Economic Forum (Box 347)
  - World Economic Forum, 7 folders (Box 348)
  - World Economic Forum, 7 folders (Box 349)
  - World Economic Forum Programme, 1995 (Oversize 14)
  - Wort, Ann (Box 349)
  - Wouk, Herman (Box 350)
  - Wright, Charles Alan (Box 350)
  - Wright, Jim (Box 350)
  - Yaqub-Khan, Sahabzada (Box 350)
  - Yavlinsky, Grigory, 5 folders (Box 350)
    See also Subject file Kozyrev, Andrei: Yavlinsky, Grigory.
  - Yellow Rain (Box 350)
  - Yeltsin, Boris (Box 350)
  - Yerkes, Susan G. (Box 350)
  - Yes, Virginia (Box 350)
  - Yew Trees (Box 350)
  - Yom Kippur parties, 1984; 1988-1990,; 1993-1994,; 1996; 7 folders (Box 350)
  - Yom Kippur parties, 1997-1998; 2003-2009; 9 folders (Box 351)
  - Young Hitler (Box 351)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 351)
  - Zarqawi, Abu Musab (Box 351)
  - Zeder, Fred (Box 351)
  - Zenith laptops (Box 351)
  - Zeos International (Box 351)
  - Zhirinovsky, Vladimir (Box 351)
  - Zogby, John (Box 351)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 351)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 19)
- Writings
  - Books
    - Before the Fall: An Inside View of the Pre-Watergate White House
      - CBS News Special: "Haldeman: The Nixon Years - Conversations with Mike Wallace (Box 492)
      - Chapter drafts, 2 folders (Box 492)
      - Correspondence (Box 493)
      - Correspondence with Doubleday (Oversize 27)
      - Draft, 17 folders (Box 493)
      - Draft, 9 folders (Box 494)
      - Fan mail (Box 494)
      - Galley proof (Box 521)
      - Galley proof (Box 522)